Preliminary Guide to the Social Democrats, USA Records, 1937-1994 (Bulk 1970-1994)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 2001-0079
  - contents of Box 50: (Box 50)
    - YSD Activities (Box 50)
    - Memoranda from Dave Peterson (Box 50)
    - National Conventions 1985-1987
      - Resolutions 1985, (three folders) (Box 50)
      - Hotel Arrangements 1985 (Box 50)
      - Committees 1985 (Box 50)
      - Contributions 1985 (Box 50)
      - Finances 1987 (Box 50)
      - NC Pre-Meeting 1987 (Box 50)
      - Committees 1987 (Box 50)
      - Delegates 1987 (Box 50)
      - Apportionment 1987 (Box 50)
      - NC Post-Meeting 1987 (Box 50)
      - National Committee 1987 (Box 50)
      - Delegate Elections MAL and Local Results 1987 (Box 50)
      - Observers (Non-Members) 1987 (Box 50)
      - Contributions 1987 (Box 50)
      - Publicity 1987 (Box 50)
      - Madison Hotel, Washington D.C., 1987 (Box 50)
      - Apportionment (Box 50)
  - contents of Box 51: (Box 51)
    - Declaration of the Unified Nicaraguan Opposition (UNO), 1985 (Box 51)
    - National Convention 1985
      - Delegates (Box 51)
      - NC Post-Meeting (Box 51)
      - Finances (Box 51)
      - Delegates Nominations MAL (Box 51)
      - Observers (Box 51)
      - L'enfant Plaza, Washington, D.C. (Box 51)
      - Apportionment (Box 51)
      - National Committee (Box 51)
      - Publicity (Box 51)
      - Photos (Box 51)
      - Delegate Elections MAL (Box 51)
      - Pledge Plan Drive (Box 51)
      - Greetings (Box 51)
      - General and Correspondence (Box 51)
      - Travel Subsidies (Box 51)
      - NC Pre-Meeting (Box 51)
      - Printed Matter, (two folders) (Box 51)
    - National Convention 1987
      - General, Correspondence and Speeches, (two folders) (Box 51)
      - Members (Non-Delegates)(Observers) (Box 51)
      - Greetings (Box 51)
      - Hotel Arrangements (Box 51)
      - Contacts and Lists (Box 51)
      - Delegate Nominations MAL (Box 51)
      - Resolutions and Policy Statements, (three folders) (Box 51)
    - New America, 1972-1978, (forty-six folders) (Box 51)
  - contents of Box 52: (Box 52)
    - Bayard Rustin
      - Articles (Box 52)
      - Seventy-fifth Birthday 1987 March 26, New York Hillton (Box 52)
      - Rustin Memorial (Box 52)
      - Bayard Rustin High School (Box 52)
      - Bayard Rustin Fund (Box 52)
      - Rustin, Bayard, (eleven folders) (Box 52)
  - contents of Box 53: (Box 53)
    - Rustin, Bayard, (two folders) (Box 53)
    - Democratic Party, (three folders) (Box 53)
    - Democratic Party, File #2 (Box 53)
    - Democratic Party, File #3, (two folders) (Box 53)
    - Michael Danby (Box 53)
    - Decter, Midge (Box 53)
    - The Defense Democrat (Box 53)
    - Delson and Gordon (Box 53)
    - Democracy Corps 1993 (Box 53)
    - The Democracy International (Box 53)
    - Democracy Roundtable (Box 53)
    - The Democratic Agenda (Box 53)
    - Daily News Strike (Box 53)
    - Daily World (Box 53)
    - DSOC, File 3, (two folders) (Box 53)
    - Newsletter of The Democratic Left, (two folders) (Box 53)
    - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (Box 53)
    - Democratic Socialists of America, (five folders) (Box 53)
    - Center for Democratic Policy (Box 53)
    - Democratic Policy Commission Conference 1986 April 11-1996 April 12 (Box 53)
    - Democratic National Committee (Box 53)
    - Democratic Convention (Box 53)
    - Democratic Party Statement (Box 53)
    - Democratic National Convention 1984 July, San Francisco, Literature (Box 53)
    - Democratic National Convention 1992 July 13-1992 July 17, New York (Box 53)
    - Disk separation sheets for 10 disks found inside a disk file (Box 53)
  - contents of Box 54: (Box 54)
    - Democratic Challenge in Latin America Conference-Lisbon, Portugal 1984 June 28-1984 June 30 (Box 54)
    - Democratic National Convention 1984 July, San Francisco, California (Box 54)
    - Young Social Democrats (YSD), Universities
      - Chicago (Box 54)
      - Columbia (Box 54)
      - Evergreen (Box 54)
      - George Washington (Box 54)
      - Minnesota (Box 54)
      - Philadelphia (Box 54)
      - NYU (Box 54)
      - New York Local (Box 54)
      - Ohio (Box 54)
      - Penn (Box 54)
      - Tufts (Box 54)
    - Washington, D.C. (Box 54)
    - Articles by SDers on SD, AFL-CIO (Box 54)
    - The Social Democrat, Spring 1975 (Box 54)
    - The Social Democrat, Summer 1982 (Box 54)
    - YIPME (Box 54)
    - Youth for Energy Independence (Box 54)
    - White House (Box 54)
    - Mondale Campaign (Box 54)
    - Network (Box 54)
    - YSD, NEC, NAC (Box 54)
    - New Members (Box 54)
    - YSD (Box 54)
    - USYC, (three folders) (Box 54)
    - NOTE (Box 54)
    - NSIC (Box 54)
    - Pastora Event (Box 54)
    - Key list (Box 54)
    - Memos 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Receipts/bills paid (Box 54)
    - Primary Campaign/Mondale Hart Jackson (Box 54)
    - RJ Reynolds Boycott (Box 54)
    - SDUSA, NC, NAC (Box 54)
    - Receipts 1983-1984 (Box 54)
    - Requests for Info (Box 54)
    - Randolph Bureau (Box 54)
    - Portugal
      - Ad 1975, (two folders) (Box 54)
      - Through 1976, (two folders) (Box 54)
      - 1978-1986 (Box 54)
      - Portugal (Box 54)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 54)
    - Poland (Box 54)
    - Poland-Jewish Relations (Box 54)
  - contents of Box 55: (Box 55)
    - SI Congress, Lima, Peru, 1986 June 20 - 1986 June 23 (Box 55)
    - SI Conference on Latin America and the Caribbean, 1980 March 26 - 1980 March 28, (two folders) (Box 55)
    - SI Congress, 1983 (Box 55)
    - SI Congress, Stockholm, Sweden, 1989 August 1 (Box 55)
    - [Photograph and prints] (Box 55)
    - American Federation of Teachers, (six folders) (Box 55)
    - The Changing Economy: Its Social Impact and Policy Implications (Box 55)
    - Breika (Box 55)
    - Irving Brown (Box 55)
    - Arnold Beichman (Box 55)
    - Daniel Bell (Box 55)
    - Matt Bergman (Box 55)
    - Melanie Berg (Box 55)
    - Galot Dreyer and Berkey (Box 55)
    - Bieringer, Steve (Box 55)
    - Black Americans to Support Israel (Basic) (Box 55)
    - James Burnett (Box 55)
    - Bernt Carlsson (Box 55)
    - Sectarian Trivia (Box 55)
    - N.Y.C. Local, 1983 (Box 55)
    - Reading List (Box 55)
    - YPSL Benefit, 1982 (Box 55)
    - SI, 1983, (two folders) (Box 55)
  - contents of Box 56: (Box 56)
    - Ryan cocktail party, 1969 March, (folder 2 of 2) (Box 56)
    - YCPDME, (folder 4 of 4) (Box 56)
    - Socialist Party Convention (Box 56)
    - Sponsors list fund (Box 56)
    - Recruitment, (folder 2 of 2) (Box 56)
    - Daily world, (folder 2 of 2) (Box 56)
    - SI Congress, Stockholm, Sweden, 1989 August 1, (folder 1 of 5) (Box 56)
  - Audio cassette tapes, (total 76 tapes)
    Young Social Democrats; YPSL, and some other SD tapes. YSD tapes include: 1984 YSD Convention; Eden Pastora at Columbia University; and Democratic Solidarity Conference.
    - contents of Box 57: (Box 57)
      - (seventeen cassette tapes, including three tapes from Box 43) (Box 57)
    - contents of Box 58: (Box 58)
      - Nineteen cassette tapes (Box 58)
    - contents of Box 59:, Twenty cassette tapes (Box 59)
    - contents of Box 60: (Box 60)
      - Twenty cassette tapes (Box 60)
  - YPSL and Socialist Party banners (Box 61)
  - Eugene V. Debs Award and Research Institute Award given to Norman Thomas, 1966 and undated (Box 62)
  - UAW Social Justice Award given to Norman Thomas, 1968 (Box 63)